Guide to the Secular Yiddish Schools in North America Collection M0732
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 1. Yiddish school files
  - Weinman, Janice. Curriculum Materials for Teachers., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 42, Folder 26)
    M. M. Krug, S. M. Blumenfield, "The One Hundredth Anniversary of the Birth of I. L. Peretz." Chicago: Board of Jewish Education of Chicago, 1952. Trilingual (Yiddish, English and Hebrew) booklet. Each section contains a biographical sketch of Peretz, plus 2-3 of his stories. The Yiddish section begins with a song, lyrics by Peretz, music by M. Gelbart. Hebrew cover has woodcut of Peretz by Isac Friedlander. Includes suggestions for school assembly programs in English. Original.
  - Weinman, Janice. Photographs. Workmen's Circle School of Skokie, Illinois, 1971 graduating class with teachers Jack Weinman and Isaac Malamedovich. Attached is note from Janice Weinman. Original., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 42, Folder 27)
  - Kirsh, Leah. Correspondence re SYSA Collection. Unsigned and undated one-page typed letter concerning the founding of the Fair Lawn, NJ Jewish secular school in 1955. English. Original., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 42, Folder 28)
  - Kirsh, Leah. Curriculum Material for Teachers. Emanuel Gamoran, "Methods of Teaching Jewish History. A Syllabus for Jewish Teachers." New York: Union of American Hebrew Congregations, 1950. 18 lessons, mostly composed of questions to the teacher concerning why and how Jewish history should be taught. Includes bibliography for pupils and teachers. English. Original. I. Goldberg, ed. "Sholem Aleichem 1959-1959." New York: Service Bureau of Jewish Education, 1959. 33-page booklet outlining biography of Sholem Aleichem. Includes bibliography and a portrait of Sholem Aleichem. Yiddish and English. Original., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 42, Folder 29)
  - Kirsh, Leah. Holiday Materials., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    No author, no editor, "Khanike. Materialn far lerer." New York: Yidisher dertsiung biuro [=Service Bureau of Jewish Education], no date. 46-page mimeographed booklet containing various plays, songs and invocations for candle-lighting. Illustrations by Herb Kruckman. Yiddish and English. Original. Philip Goodman, ed., "Hanukah. Program Material for Young Adults and Adults." New York: Jewish Center Division of the National Jewish Welfare Board, 1953. 74-page mimeographed booklet containing blessings, Hanukah traditions around the world, plays, poems, games, songs with and without musical notation, refreshments, arts and crafts projects, stories and discussion topics. English. Original. Carl Wasserman, compiler, "Passover Haggadah/Hagode shel pesakh. Peninsula Jewish Folk Shule. Far Rockaway, NY. 1962." 9-page mimeographed booklet. Illustrations by Bernette Rudolph. English, Yiddish and Hebrew. Original. Lewis M. Moroze, ed. "Passover Haggadah." Newark: Danfred Publishers, 1965. 21-page printed booklet. Handwritten on cover: "Prop[erty] F.[air] L.[awn] Jewish Childrens School." Printed on inside cover: "Dedicated to the memory of James Chaney, Andrew Goodman, Michael Schwirmer [sic]". Illustrations by William Vigoda. English. Original. Carl Wasserman, compiler, "Passover Haggadah/ Hagode shel pesakh. Fairlawn Jewish Schildren's School. Fair Lawn, NJ. 1966." 9-page mimeographed booklet. English, Yiddish and Hebrew. Original.
  - Rubenstein, Adrienne. Diplomas, Report Cards, Certificates. Promotion certificates for 1962, 1963, 1964 for "Eydele Rubenshteyn", Sholem Aleichem Shul 21 (Bronx). Report cards for "Eydele Rubenshteyn" from Sholem Aleichem Shul 21, 1961-62, 1962-63, 1963-64, 1964-65. Yiddish and English. Originals., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Rubenstein, Adrienne. Souvenir Journals. Sholem Aleichem Folkshul 7, Perth Amboy, NJ, 1948. Cover and 2 pages of photos professionally reproduced, the rest mimeographed. Yiddish. Sholem Aleichem Folk Shul 21, Bronx, NY, June 1964. Professionally printed. English and Yiddish. Sholem Aleichem Folk Shul 21, Bronx, NY, June 1965. Professionally printed. English and Yiddish. All originals., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Rubenstein, Adrienne. Administrative/Organiza-tional Materials. Postcards giving notice of school meetings. Sholem Aleichem Folk Shul 1, Bronx, addressed to Mr. and Mrs. A. Schweid, June 1943. Sholem Aleichem Folk Shul 21, Bronx, addressed to Gella Fishman, March 1970. Yiddish. Originals., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Vishner, Ira. Songs: Music and Lyrics. Undzer gezang. Lider zamlung far der yidisher shul. Montreal, 1929. Dedication to "shul kinder tsum fuftsn yorikn yubileum fun di yidishe folks shuln, Montreal." Lyrics only, Yiddish and some Hebrew (114 pages of songs, plus index). Original. Also M. Gelbart, ed. Lomir zingen. 61 lider far heym, shul, yontoyvim un fayerungen. New York: Arbeter Ring Education Committee, 1937-38. 95 pp. Yiddish text and musical notation for all songs. Includes Yiddish versions by M. Gelbart of non-Jewish songs such as "Old Black Joe" and "Funiculi Funicula." Original. Also songsheets for holidays and commemorations, including songbook for WC/AR youth group reunion, 11/83. Yiddish and English, lyrics only. Originals., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Vishner, Ira. Holiday Materials. Purim (March 1961 and March 1962) and Chanukah (no date) supplements attached to PTA newsletter for Sholem Aleichem Shul 21, Bronx, NY. Activity suggestions, news of celebrations, songsheets. Mostly English with a little Yiddish., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Vishner, Ira. School Newsletters and Bulletins. Sholem Aleichem Shul 21 News, Feb., Apr., Dec. 1960; Mar., May 1961; Jan., Apr. Nov. 1962; Feb. 1963; Nov. 1965. Includes a few songsheets. English. Mimeographed originals., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Vishner, Ira. Souvenir Journals [1 of 3], Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    Sholem Aleichem Folkshul 21, Bronx, NY. 1957, 1958, 1960, 1961, 1962, 1963, 1964, 1966. 1970, 1971, 1972. Yiddish and English. Originals.
  - Vishner, Ira. Souvenir Journals [2 of 3], Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Vishner, Ira. Souvenir Journals [3 of 3], Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Vishner, Ira. Yiddish Summer Camp Materials, Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    Song book "Lomir zingen lider," compiled by Michael Baran for Arbeter Ring, 1982. Mimeographed. Yiddish and English. Original. "Camp Boiberik Shabes Lider." Yiddish, Hebrew and transliterated English. No date. Original. Also "Boiberik zingt." Yiddish, English and Hebrew songs, including American folksongs and transliteration of Yiddish and Hebrew. 1961. Original. Also "Camp Kinder Ring Alumni Directory, 60th Anniversary Reunion." English. No date. Original. "Kindervelt zingt." Yiddish and Hebrew songs from Camp Kindervelt (Farband). 55 songs, first 8 pages in Yiddish and Hebrew, last 8 in transliterated English of the foregoing songs. 1938. Original.
  - Vishner, Ira. Newspaper Clippings., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    Three copies of the same pages of Der tog, 11 Feb. 1961 (front-page headline concerning Patrice Lumumba's escape from prison). Column entitled "esseyen fun kinder vos hoben gevunen priv [sic]" contains essays from 4 students in Arbeter Ring and Sholem Aleichem schools in New York. Yiddish. Original (very fragile newsprint) plus photocopies.
  - Vishner, Ira. Administrative/Organizational Materials., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    Composition book containing handwritten minutes of the United Mitlshul Parents Association (New York) meetings. Minutes from 6/1/64 - 3/7/66. English. Original. Also individual items of official correspondence to and from people associated with Sholem Aleichem shul 21 (Bronx, NY), as a school and a cultural center, 1960-1978. Also financial statements with some membership lists of SA shul 21 students (1960) and center members (1974-75). Mostly handwritten and undated. English. Originals.
  - Vishner, Ira. Personal Correspondence., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    Letter from Ira Vishner to Gella Fishman concerning his mother Esther Vishner and her papers, dated 9 Aug. 2000. English. Original. Also a note from M. Goldstein to Esther Vishner, June 1966. Yiddish. Original. Includes photo of a group Group of people in SA Folkshul 21 Center, 1978. Notations of names on back in English. Original
  - Greenhouse, Muriel. Memoirs: Published and Unpublished., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    One-page composition entitled "A Sholem Aleichem Folk Shule Love Story" concerning lives of "Bosha Brandwein and Moisha Greenhouse". Included are medals awarded to "Moish" and "Bosh" when they graduated from Sholem Aleichem Folk Shule andandx0023;7 in Perth Amboy, New Jersey. Compositioncomputer printed. English. Original.
  - Greenhouse, Muriel. Photographs, Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    andandx0023;1: Yugend Club of Sholem Aleichem Folk Shul andandx0023;7, Perth Amboy, NJ, 1941. Names annotated on back in English. Photocopy. andandx0023;2: Sholem Aleichem Folk Shul andandx0023;7, Perth Amboy, NJ, first student body, 1921. Photocopy. andandx0023;3: Sholem Aleichem Folk Shul andandx0023;7, Perth Amboy, NJ, Farvalter un froyen verein, 1941. Names annotated on back in English. Original. andandx0023;4: Sholem Aleichem Folk Shul andandx0023;7, Perth Amboy, NJ. Oneg shabes (student participation), 1956. Original. andandx0023;5: Sholem Aleichem Folk Shul andandx0023;7, Perth Amboy, NJ, Hanukkah celebration, 1955. Original. andandx0023;6: Sholem Aleichem Folk Shul andandx0023;7, Perth Amboy, NJ, 1940-41. Adult choral group led by Ben Yomen. Names annotated on back in English. Original. andandx0023;7: Sholem Aleichem Folk Shul andandx0023;7, Perth Amboy, NJ, 1940. Froyen verein. Names annotated on back in English. Original. andandx0023;8: Sholem Aleichem Folk Shul andandx0023;7, Perth Amboy, NJ, 1940). Yugend Club annual dinner. Names annotated on back in English. Original.. andandx0023;9: English newspaper clipping (10/20/39) reprodu-cing photo of cast of "Around the Family Table" performed by Sholem Aleichem Folk Shul andandx0023;7, Perth Amboy, NJ, 1939. Original. andandx0023;10: Cast of "Around the Family Table," performed by Yugend Club. Original. andandx0023;11: Clipping photo and article re Sholem Aleichem Folk Shul andandx0023;7, Perth Amboy, NJ high school graduation (3/23/39). English. Originals. andandx0023;12: Sholem Aleichem Folk Shul andandx0023;7, Perth Amboy, NJ, 1938. Graduating class. Names annotated on back. English. Original. andandx0023;13 (photo labeled "andandx0023;14"): Sholem Aleichem Folk Shul andandx0023;7, Perth Amboy, NJ, 1951. Purim shpil. English. Original. andandx0023;15: Sholem Aleichem Folk Shul andandx0023;7, Perth Amboy, NJ, 1954. Chanukah celebration. English. Original.
  - Fuchsman, Charles. Memoirs: Published and Unpublished., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    Evocation of Joseph Wall, Yiddish teacher in Sholem Aleichem Folkshul andandx0023;4, Bronx, NY, in 1929-30. English. Original. Includes cover letter to Gella Fishman.
  - Gross, Mindy C. Memoirs: Published and Un- published., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    Evocation of Edna Kogan, teacher in Sholem Aleichem shul andandx0023;11, Brooklyn, NY. No date. Yiddish. Photocopy.
  - Gross, Mindy C. Diplomas., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    Sholem Aleichem Folk Institut for Mindl Cristol, graduated from folkshul andandx0023;11 in June 1945. Yiddish. Also Sholem Aleichem Folk Institut, Mindl Cristol, graduated from Sholem Aleichem mitlshul in June 1945. Yiddish. Photocopies. Includes photograph of graduating class of Sholem Aleichem folkshul andandx0023;11 in June 1945. Includes Mindy Cristol and Edna Kogan. Photocopy.
  - Herman, Marge. Photographs, Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    Arbeter Ring shul in Boyle Heights (Los Angeles, CA), 1934-35. Original in Los Angeles Times newspaper article 3/1/2000. Also enlarged photocopy. Also photo of Arbeter Ring shul in Boyle Heights, 126 St. Louis Street, Los Angeles, 1938. Notation of names in English on back. Includes teacher, the poet Malke Tussman. Photocopy.
  - Honig, Alice. Memoirs: Published and Unpublished., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 44, Folder 10)
    Evocation of teacher Miss Nakdemon in "folkshule" (possibly Farband) in Brooklyn, NY ((Empire Blvd. Near Brooklyn Ave.) in the 1930s and 1940s. English. Original.
  - Bergman, Hannah. Obituaries, Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    For Israel M. Goodelman, author of the "Yidishe geshikhte heftn", published by Farlag Matones of the Sholem Aleichem Folk Institute. Obituary appeared in December 1966 in Kinder zhurnal. Yiddish. Photocopy. Includes explanatory letter from Goodelman's daughter Hannah Bergman. English. Original.
  - Lederhendler, Blume. Speeches., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    Given at graduation ceremony from Sholem Aleichem mitlshul, NY, June 1944. Entitled ""Yidishe geshikhte durkh der yidisher poeziye." Also: speech delivered by B. Lederhendler in Sholem Aleichem shul 21 (Bronx, NY) at a gathering honoring the Lederhendler family upon their moving to Israel in June, 1974. Also: Speech to friends of SA shul 21, 1947-48, by B. Chinsky (Lederhendler). Also speech to friends and board members of SA shul 21, 1946-47, "Khanike un dos yidish kind." Also speech to adolescents at SA shul 21 re Hanukkah, between 1957-60. Also speech to adolescents at SA shul 21 re Hanukkah, 1947-48. All handwritten Yiddish. Also speech by B. Chinsky presenting the poet Avrom Reyzen at shul 21, 1947. Also Sara Lederhendler's graduation speech about the Baal Shem Tov. June 1965. Yiddish. Photocopy. Also speech for a graduation ceremony in the 1960s about poet A. Reyzn by M. Goldshteyn and B. Lederhendler. Includes some of Reyzn's poems. Yiddish. Original.
  - Lederhendler, Blume. Student Writings, Published and Unpublished., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    Paper written in last year of Sholem Aleichem mitlshul, 1943-44: "Dos harts fun yidishn folk." Also a composition written by B. Chinsky (Lederhendler) for SA mitlshul in 1940, "dos hintl." Stapled to graduation speech given by B. Chinsky from SA folkshul 4, Bronx, NY, 1940; stapled to graduation ceremony flier for SA mitlshul, June 1944 and invitation to "oyneg shabes" flier, Jan 1945 (typed Yiddish, photocopy). Handwritten Yiddish. Photocopy. Also by Blume Chinsky. "Meynungen fun talmidim vegn der americaner yidisher shul," in Shul pinkes, 1948, pp. 521-25. Yiddish. Photocopy. Also various compositions by Melekhl Lederhendler, 1962-63. Yiddish. 2 originals, rest photocopies.
  - Lederhendler, Blume. Holiday Materials., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 44, Folder 14)
    "Hagode far yugntlekhe." Prepared by Shmuel Lapin and Blume Chinsky, printed by Sholem Aleichem Yugnt-gezelshaft (according to notations by B. Lederhendler, composed of SA mitlshul graduates from 1946-48). No date. Yiddish. Mimeo original. Also "Hagode shel pesakh" for Sholem Aleichem shul 21, 1970. Yiddish. Photocopy. Also sheets for oyneg shabos songs, decorative map of Israel for Yom Hatzmaut, sheet with the 4 Questions in Hebrew and Yiddish, template for homework certificate for preschoolers. Yiddish. Photocopies. Also a song sheet for Pesach with brief explanations of what the 5 songs included mean. No date. Yiddish and English. Origianl. Also a program for a "Youth Oyneg Shabos" at SA shul 21, 11/69. Yiddish and English. Original. Also a reading for a Chanukah program at Sholem Aleichem shul 21, no date. Yiddish. Photocopy. Also a notebook of poetry, songs and recitations for oyneg shabes programs at Sholem Aleichem shul 21, 1957-58; another for 1958-59. Yiddish. Also leaflet inviting people to oyneg shabes where Blanche Chinsky would speak on "Jewish History Through Jewish Poetry". Jan. 1945. Yiddish and English. Photocopy.
  - Lederhendler, Blume. Examinations., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 44, Folder 15)
    Exam given to first-year students in all Sholem Aleichem shuln in New York. 1965, take by Zahava Lederhendler. Also exam taken by Blume Chinsky at the Lerers seminar (NY) in April 1947, entitled "Ekzamen metodik in yidish." 19 manuscript pages. Yiddish. Photocopy.
  - Lederhendler, Blume. Songs: Music and Lyrics., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 44, Folder 16)
    Songs from the play by M. Gilinski, Lialkes, music by J. Troupianski. Warsaw: Kooperativer Farlag "Kultur-lige," 1937. P. 2 notes: "A matone fun der Medem Sanatorie far di kinder fun di arbeter ring shuln." Yiddish. Photocopy. Attached are sheets for the choral text of Lialkes as performed in Sholem Aleichem shul 21, 1964. Yiddish. Original. Lyrics of alphabet song for first-year children. Yiddish. Original. Spring concert song sheet, SA folkshul. May 1944. 12 songs. Yiddish. Original.
  - Lederhendler, Blume. Tributes., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 44, Folder 17)
    Tribute to teacher M. Goldshteyn of SA shul 21 from students and former students. Printed in Yidisher Kemfer, organ of the Poale Zion Organization of America 1958. Yiddish. Photocopy. Also letter written by Blume Lederhendler to be read on the first anniversary of teacher M. Goldshteyn's death. Read by her son Elimelekh at a memorial meeting held in Sholem Aleichem shul 21. No date.
  - Lederhendler, Blume. Photographs., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 44, Folder 18)
    Graduating class of Sholem Aleichem mitlshul, NY, 1944. Annotated in Yiddish. Also photo of graduating students in all Sholem Aleichem folkshuln in New York, May 1940. Annotated in Yiddish. Also photo of graduating class, Lerers seminar, New York, 1949. Attached are: program from graduation exercises and graduation speech by Blume Chinsky. Annotated in Yiddish. Also photos, Sholem Aleichem shul 21 graduating classes, 1947, 1948 (orig.), 1967 (orig.),1970. Annotated in Yiddish. Photocopies unless otherwise noted. Also assorted photos of events at Sholem Aleichem shul 21 from 1958 to 1970 (some undated). Annotations in Yiddish. Originals and copies.
  - Lederhendler, Blume. Personal Correspondence., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 44, Folder 19)
    Letter from SA shul 21 teacher M. Goldshteyn to Melekhl Lederhendler, age 9, congratulating him on winning second place for good conduct. June 1962. Handwritten Yiddish. Photocopy. Also form letter from SA shul 21 teacher M. Goldshteyn to Zahava Lederhendler, congraulating her on winning the good conduct prize. June 1969. Yiddish. Photocopy
  - Lederhendler, Blume. Affiliated Organizations., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 44, Folder 20)
    Report of minutes from Youth Federation (four clubs), 1946-47, by secretary Blume Chinsky. Yiddish. Photocopy.
  - Lederhendler, Blume. Newsletters., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 44, Folder 21)
    PTA newsletter for Sholem Aleichem shul 21, Oct. 1960. Also newsletters re book fair at SA shul 21, Nov. 1963 and Nov. 1965. English. Originals. Also newsletter, Nov. 1968. English. Photocopy.
  - Lederhendler, Blume. Student Notebooks and Class Notes., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 44, Folder 22)
    2 beginner notebooks of Sarah Lederhendler, 1960 and 1961. Have lines typical of Yiddish cursive notebooks, but the covers (beginning at left) have "Writing Book" "The Property of __________" printed on it. Back covers have measuring tables (avoirdupois, liquid, etc.). Insides contain cursive Yiddish exercises, some corrected. Also: Notebook of Sarah Lederhendler, 1961-62. Contains 7"x8" lined paper, English school notebook. Contains exercises in cursive Yiddish (some corrected), photos cut from magazines and pasted in, a Purim songsheet. Also :copy of cover of notebook entitled "Sholem Aleichem shul," printed by SAFI. Copy of back cover shows lists of Yiddish words that come from Hebrew. Yiddish No date (photocopy). All others Yiddish originals.
  - Lederhendler, Blume. Pedagogical Materials: Yiddish Language., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 44, Folder 23)
    Various stencils containing the Ten Commandments, dramatic readings, fables; one handwritten. Used in first class of SA shul 21 in the 1960s. Yiddish. Originals.
  - Lederhendler, Blume. Souvenir Journals [1 of 2], Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 44, Folder 24)
    Sholem Aleichem folkshul 4, Bronx, NY, graduation journal, June 1941. Also Sholem Aleichem mitlshul souvenir journal, 1944, "Di shtim." Also Sholem Aleichem folkshul 21, June 1947, June 1964, June 1969 June 1970. Also United Mitlshul, New York, 1966. All Yiddish and English. Originals. Also Sholem Aleichem folkshul 21, June 1965. Yiddish and English. Photocopy.
  - Lederhendler, Blume. Souvenir Journals [2 of 2], Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 44, Folder 25)
  - Lederhendler, Blume. Publications for Children., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    Kinder tsaytung, Sept./Oct. 1968. Also Kinder zhurnal, Fall 1973. Yiddish. Originals.
  - Lederhendler, Blume. Diplomas Report Cards and Graduation Announcements and Certificates., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    Invitation to and program for SA shul 21 graduation, June 1970. Invitation Yiddish and English; program flier Yiddish. Originals. Also graduation program flier, SA shul 21, June 1965. Yiddish. Photocopy. Also report card from "Yidishe folk shul" in New Bedford, MA, 1932, for "Blimele Chinsky," class alef. Yiddish. Photocopy. Also report card from SA shul 21, 1962-63 for Melekh Lederhendler, terms 7-8. Yiddish and English. Original.
  - Lederhendler, Blume. Informational Material., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    Brief (1-page) review of curriculum at SA shul 21. English. Original.
  - Lederhendler, Blume. School Performances and Scripts for School Plays., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    Narration and choral recitations led by teacher M. Goldshteyn and written by I. Goikhberg, "Dos ponim fun undzer folk," Sholem Aleichem shul 21, June 1964. Yiddish. Photocopy. Script for younger class "ariberfir yontif," 1961. Yiddish. Photocopy. Script for a program about Yiddish folksongs including names of narrators, choral and solo singers. 1960s. Yiddish. Original. Script of "Lakhn iz gezunt, " a Sholem Aleichem play arranged by Y. Mlotek for shul 21, 1969-70. Yiddish. Original. Program for Jewish Music Month, SA shul 21, March 1967. Dramatic reading with music, Di eybike keyt.. Spring concert, 1944. Yiddish. Original. Poem by A. Reyzn, "Di lererin mire" set to music and presented by SA folkshul 21, 1963? Musical notation written out by Sarah Lederhendler in 1990. Yiddish. Photocopy. Program of A. Goldfadn songs sung by children's chorus. Attached is songsheet with abbreviated versions of six songs. Yiddish and English. Originals. Dramatic reading for Shvues, SA shul 21, 1971. Includes text of songs. Yiddish. Photocopy. Also narration about I.L. Peretz written by M. Goldshtein and performed by the whole graduating class of shul 21, 1965. Yiddish. Photocopy. Graduation speech by Zahava Lederhendler, shul 21, 1970. Yiddish. Photocopy. Midyear concert program, 1964, with list of songs sung by children's chorus. Attached is cast of characters and actors for play Lialkes. Midyear concert program, 1965. Yiddish. Photocopies. Script for recitation, "Ven vet zayn morgn?", prepared by Blume Lederhendler for shul 21, 1962-63. Yiddish. Photocopy.
  - Lederhendler, Blume. Administrative Material., Accession no. 2001-083 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    Blank tuition fee card, SA shul 21. Around 1960. Yiddish and English. Original.
  - Margolis, Chassie. Photographs., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Barkan, Hershl. Diplomas, Report Cards, Graduation Announcements and Certificates., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Greenberg, Dina. Diplomas, Report Cards, Graduation Announcements and Certificates., Accession no. 1994-157 (Box 1, Folder 3)